Mss.Ms.Coll.56
American Philosophical Society
- I. Correspondence, Bulk, 1986-2006; 1967-2006; 5.0 Linear feet 13 boxes; Leopold, Luna B. (Luna Bergère), 1915-2006
  - 2. Correspondence Identified Only by Familiar Names and Undetermined, 0.5 ln. ft. 2 boxes
    - Cathy, 2003-2005 (Box 12)
    - Charlie and Lorrie, 1992, 1994 (Box 12)
    - Chi, 1986 (Box 12)
    - CK, 1987 (Box 12)
    - Claude and Michel, 1994 (Box 12)
    - Colin, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Connee, 1978 (Box 12)
    - Cort, undated (Box 12)
      Feather included in one piece of correspondence.
    - Curt, 2004 (Box 12)
    - D and [?], 1993 (Box 12)
    - Dave, Kae and Brandon, undated (Box 12)
    - Dave, undated (Box 12)
    - Deric, undated (Box 12)
    - Dick, 2005 (Box 12)
    - Dolores and John, undated (Box 12)
    - Donna, undated (Box 12)
    - Elaine M. W., 2000 (Box 12)
    - Ellen W. G., 1996, 1999 (Box 12)
    - Eric and Adele, 1989; undated (Box 12)
    - Eve and Herb, 1987 (Box 12)
    - Fran, undated (Box 12)
    - George, 1999 (Box 12)
    - Isabelle and Nochenka, 2001; undated (Box 12)
    - Jack, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Janet, undated (Box 12)
    - Jed M., 1987 (Box 12)
      Correspondence from a young child.
    - Jo, 1994 (Box 12)
    - Joan, 1993, 2002-2005 (Box 12)
    - Joe and Debbie, undated (Box 12)
    - Joel, undated (Box 12)
    - John (1), undated (Box 12)
    - John (2), 1979-1980 (Box 12)
    - John and Beth, 1986, 1990 (Box 12)
    - John and Terresa, 2001 (Box 12)
    - Johnny, 1982 (Box 12)
    - Josie, undated (Box 12)
    - Karen, 1980, 1986; undated (Box 12)
    - Karen and John L., undated (Box 12)
    - Kath, 1986 (Box 12)
    - Kathleen and Bob, 1992, 1994 (Box 12)
    - Kay, undated (Box 12)
    - Lee S., 1993, 1998 (Box 12)
    - Linda and John, undated (Box 12)
    - Lynn, 1987 (Box 12)
    - Marc, undated (Box 12)
    - Margaret N., 1999 (Box 12)
    - Mary, Andrew and Jack, 1984; undated (Box 12)
    - Mary and Ned, 1994 (Box 12)
    - Mary Lou, undated (Box 12)
      Not Mary Lou Brown, nor Mary-Louise Quinn.
    - Matt (1), 2004 (Box 12)
    - Matt (2) and Susan, 2004; undated (Box 12)
    - Melanie, undated (Box 12)
    - Michael (1), 1993 (Box 12)
    - Michael (2), 1998 (Box 12)
    - Michele and Phil, 1986 (Box 12)
    - Mickey, 1978 (Box 12)
    - Nan and Bob, 2002 (Box 12)
    - Nancy, 2000 (Box 12)
    - Niki and Bruce, 1985, 2000 (Box 12)
    - Pat, 1978 (Box 12)
    - Peter and Lisa, undated (Box 12)
    - Ray, 1975, 1980 (Box 13)
    - Raymond, undated (Box 13)
    - Roger and Kae, 1993 (Box 13)
    - Sam, 1987 (Box 13)
      Correspondent is a young boy, nephew of Luna and Barbara Leopold.
    - Sara, 2000, 2005 (Box 13)
    - Sarah and Pat, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Scott, 2003 (Box 13)
    - Sheri and Bill, 2002 (Box 13)
    - Susan, undated (Box 13)
    - Tawnya and Mark, 2004 (Box 13)
    - Tom, 1985-1993; undated (Box 13)
      Not: Thomas Nolan.
    - Tony, 1994 (Box 13)
    - Trish, Gordon and Hanna, undated (Box 13)
    - Undetermined Correspondents (Box 13)
    - Unsorted Greeting Cards, 1985, 1995; undated (Box 13)
    - Unsigned Correspondence (Box 13)
- II. Correspondence. Ralph A. Bagnold-Luna B. Leopold, 1956-1988; undated; 0.5 Linear feet 2 boxes
  Series II comprises the three-decade correspondence received by Leopold from British colleague Ralph A. Bagnold, prominent desert explorer, sedimentary geomorphologist of desert terrains, and theoretical hydrologist. This series was the first group of Luna Leopold Papers to be received by the APS, in 1988.
  Leopold's outgoing correspondence to Bagnold was written in longhand with no copies retained; and Bagnold did not keep the correspondence he received from Leopold (fide Leopold to "Kevin" [Thomas Kevin Cherry, Mellon Library Intern, APS], 1991, correspondence in APS Manuscripts Dept. Legal File for Leopold).
  Other papers and correspondence of R.A. Bagnold are in the Churchill Archives Centre, Cambridge (U.K.).
  - Biographical Information (Box 14)
    File contains information prepared for the orginal Bagnold-Leopold Correspondence accession by APS as Ms. Coll. 56; now incorporated as Series II within the later-received Luna Leopold Papers (Ms. Coll. 56).
  - Correspondence. 1956 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence. 1957 February-September (Box 14)
    Includes Bagnold manuscript, "Prototype Rivers", 1957 February 27
  - Correspondence. 1957 October 6-7 (Box 14)
    Includes Bagnold manuscript, "River Behaviour. From the bases of Dynamics, Least Work, and Entropy".
  - Correspondence. 1957 October 19 (Box 14)
    Includes Bagnold manuscript, "River flow round a bend".
  - Correspondence. 1957 October 24-November (Box 14)
  - Correspondence. 1958 (Box 14)
    Includes "Suggestions of Brig. Bagnold on Needed Research", 1958 March 5.
  - Correspondence. 1959 March 16-July 10 (Box 14)
    Includes Bagnold manuscripts: [1] "Paths of Flow and Their Relation to Turbulent Mixing. March 30, 1959. Suggested draft for discussion of jet-impingement concept". [2] "Direct measurement of the transport rate of bed load in saltation along a river bed".
  - Correspondence. 1959 July 14-August (Box 14)
    Includes: U.S. Geological Survey memorandum of Luna B. Leopold, 1959 July 19, "Critical Experiments in Alluvial Channel Hydraulics". U.S. Geological Survey memorandum of Thomas Maddock, Jr., 1959 August 17, "Research program in hydraulics of channels with moveable beds".
  - Correspondence. 1959 September-November (Box 14)
  - Correspondence. 1960 (Box 14)
    Includes Bagnold manuscript, "DRAFT - R A Bagnold 5-9-60 'Concentration'".
  - Correspondence. 1961 (Box 14)
    Includes: Bagnold manuscript list, 1961 May, "Critical Experiments Worth Doing". Bagnold manuscript, "Autosuspension of Transported Sediment. Turbidity Currents".
  - Correspondence. 1962 (Box 14)
    Includes: U.S. Geological Survey memorandum of Ivan Barnes, 1962 June 5, "Entropy of Streams". U.S. Geological Survey memorandum of Ivan Barnes, 1962 October 26, "Landscape formation by solution". U.S. Geological Survey memorandum of F. E. Clarke, 1962 December 26, "Bagnold's slope theory".
  - Correspondence. 1963 January-June (Box 14)
    Includes: [1] U.S. Geological Survey memorandum of H. A. Swenson, "Bagnold's theories on watershed profiles." [2] Bagnold manuscript, 1963 April 25, "Aqueous Weathering and Hill Profiles--Effects of the Solution Process". [3] [Leopold?] memorandum, 1963 June 1, "Status and Short-term Plan for Channel Research".
  - Correspondence. 1963 August-December (Box 14)
    1963 August 21: see also Oversize Box 1, Folder 1.
  - Correspondence. 1964 January (Box 14)
    Includes Bagnold manuscript, "A tentative approach to river physics".
  - Correspondence. 1964 March-December (Box 14)
    Includes U.S. Geological Survey memorandum of Ivan Johnson, 1964 October 30, "Research - Bagnold's plot for particle size".
  - Correspondence. 1965 February-April 9 (Box 14)
    Includes Leopold memorandum re Bagnold manuscript, "Comments on the Draft of the Paper Entitled 'The Basic Physics of Sediment Transport'". File also contains additional USGS memoranda re this manuscript: C. F. Nordin, Jr.; H. P. Guy; Thomas Maddock, Jr.; W. B. Langbein.
  - Correspondence. 1965 April 30-December (Box 14)
    Includes correspondence: Colby, Bruce R. to Bagnold, 1965 April 30. Lansing, Alfred to Leopold, 1965 August 31, 1965 September 19.
  - Correspondence. 1966 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence. 1967 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence. 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence. 1969 (Box 14)
    Includes: [1] Manuscript, "Comments on East Fork bed-load Data 1969". [2] U.S. Geological Survey memorandum from Ed Helley and Winchell Smith, 1969 December 12, "Helley-Smith Bedload Sampler - A summary of the December 8th Meeting".
  - Correspondence. 1970 January-June (Box 14)
    Includes: Manuscript, "The natural size-distribution of heterogeneous bed-load transport". Correspondence, Edwin B. Eckel to Leopold, 1970 June 30 re Bagnold award of Penrose Medal from Geological Society of America.
    1970 January 2. See also Oversize Box 1, Folder 1.
  - Correspondence. 1970 July-October (Box 14)
    Includes Bagnold manuscript, "Response by R. A. Bagold; Penrose Medalist 1970".
  - Correspondence. 1971 (Box 14)
    Includes Bagnold manuscript, "Useful information on river conditions relevent to bed-load measurement", 1971 September 2.
    1971 December 17: see also Oversize Box 1, Folder 1.
  - Correspondence. 1972 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence. 1973 (Box 14)
    Includes Bagnold manuscript, "The width/depth ratio of a natural unconstrained river", 1973 November 10.
  - Correspondence. 1974 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence. 1975 (Box 15)
    Includes: [1] Bagnold manuscript, "Calculated bed-load transport rates from 1974 East fork river data." 1975 July 6. [2] Correspondence, Bagnold to "Bill", 1975 November 14, 1975 November 27.
  - Correspondence. 1976 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence. 1977 (Box 15)
    Includes correspondence: Bagnold to "Bill", 1977 January 28.
  - Correspondence. 1978 (Box 15)
    Includes: Correspondence, Gerald M. Friedman to Bagnold (Copy), 1978 March 17; correspondence, Friedman to Leopold, 1978 May 1. Manuscript [from a folder marked "Bagnold 1978"], "A More General Bedload Stream-Power Relationship". Manuscript by Leopold, "Citation for the Sorby Medal, 1978" re Bagnold recipient.
    1978 November 1: see also Oversize Box 1, Folder 1
  - Correspondence. 1979 (Box 15)
    Includes Bagnold manuscript, "A More General Bedload Stream-Power Relationship".
  - Correspondence. 1980 (Box 15)
    Includes Bagnold manuscript, "The Nature of Random Distributions".
  - Correspondence. 1981 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence. 1982 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence. 1985 (Box 15)
    Includes: [1] Photocopy of paper by Bagnold, "Sediment Transport by Wind and Water", Nordic Hydrology, Vol. 10 (1979), p. 309-322. [2] Bagnold manuscript, "Transport of granular solids by wind and water compared", annotated by Leopold, "Submitted for publication fall of 1985".
  - Correspondence. 1986 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence. 1988 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence. 198-, circa 1985 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence. Undated (Box 15)
    Includes: [1] Bagnold holograph manuscript, "Water resources of North African Desert". [2] Bagnold holograph manuscript, "Recharge of ground water". [3] Bagnold holograph manuscript, "Notes on measurement of directional permeability in unconsolidated rock". [4] Bagnold manuscript, "Laboratory Meanders." [5] Bagnold manuscript, "Mechanics of River Meanders." [6] Bagnold manuscript, "Karman's constant in non-homogeneous flow". [7] Bagnold manuscript, "An Empirical Correlation of Bedload Transport Rates in Flume and Natural Rivers".
  - Miscellaneous Research Notes and Graphs, undated (Box 15)
    See also Oversize Box 1, Folder 2.
- III. Correspondence with Organizations, 0.25 Linear feet 1/2 box
  Series III comprises Leopold's correspondence with organizations and professional societies, which he had segregated into separate folders. There is also some pertinent organizational correspondence that he had retained in his chronological correspondence; for which see in Series I, Subseries 1.
  - Aldo Leopold Foundation, 2004-2006 (Box 16)
    Aldo Leopold Foundation organizational correspondence will also be found in Series 1, Subseries 1, as part of correspondence with family members.
  - Aldo Leopold Foundation Conference, 2004-2006; undated (Box 16)
  - Aldo Leopold Legacy Center, 2004 (Box 16)
  - Aldo Leopold Nature Center, 2004 (Box 16)
  - Aldo Leopold Shack Foundation; Sand County Foundation, 1994 (Box 16)
    Aldo Leopold Shack Foundation organizational correspondence will also be found in Series 1, Subseries 1, as part of correspondence with family members.
  - American Philosophical Society, 1994-2005; undated (Box 16)
  - Geological Society of America, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Museum of the Mountain Man, 2002-2004; undated (Box 16)
- IV. Correspondence with Publishers, 0.25 Linear feet 1/2 box
  Series IV comprises Leopold's correspondence with publishers, which he had segregated into separate folders. There is also some pertinent publishers' correspondence that he had retained in his chronological correspondence; for which see in Series I, Subseries 1. (Some of these other publishers' correspondence may be with commercial publishers as well as the publications arms of professional societies.)
  - Annual Review of Earth and Planetary Sciences, 2002-2003 (Box 16)
  - Dover Publications, undated (Box 16)
  - Harvard University Press (Folder 1), 1993 (Box 16)
    Principally correspondence and papers relating to "A View of the River".
  - Harvard University Press (Folder 2), 1994 (Box 16)
  - Harvard University Press/Island Press, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Permission Requests Sent, 1993 (Box 16)
    Relates to "A View of the River".
  - Permissions Obtained, 1993 (Box 16)
  - University Science Books, 1974-1997 (Box 16)
  - W. H. Freeman and Co./Dover Publications, 1994-1996 (Box 16)
- V. Personal, 1.25 lin. feet 4 boxes
  Series V comprises papers, records, and ephemera of a more personal and routine nature to Luna Leopold.
  - 1. Principal Personal Papers and Ephemera
    Subseries 1 includes personal materials and ephemera; correspondence is included in some files. His foreign-travel records, like his correspondence collections, do not separate personal matters from those that are professional in nature, inasmuch as Leopold took the opportunity to pursue his professional interests during what otherwise also were pleasure trips for him and his wife. It is apparent, too, that Leopold had interests in family genealogy, although none of the genealogically related papers here will be suitably informative for in-depth research by interested genealogists.
    - Address Books, undated (Box 17)
    - Aldo Leopold Wilderness Research Institute (U.S. Forest Service). Charter, 1993 (Box 17)
      Photocopy.
    - Awards and Honors, 1989, 1992, 2006 (Box 17)
    - Awards and Honors. Luna B. Leopold support for others., 1986, 2001 (Box 17)
    - Barbara Beck Leopold Memorial. Announcement Proof Sheets, 2004 (Box 17)
    - Bergère Family Reunion, 2002 (Box 17)
      General notice only.
    - Biographical Information, 1972-2001 (Box 17)
    - Bookplates, undated (Box 17)
    - Business Card, undated (Box 17)
    - Business Cards Collected, undated; 1.0 vol. (Box 17)
      A large looseleaf volume containing hundreds of business cards (professional and personal), in no particular order.
    - Ceremonies and Dinners, 2000, 2004 (Box 17)
    - District of Columbia. Board of Registration, 1957 (Box 17)
      Regarding Sublette Co., Wyoming, property; registration no. 3857, 30 November 1957. Annotation written on verso of unrelated correspondence from "Peter", dated "19 April".
    - Elouise Luna de Bergere Trust/Aldo Leopold Children's Trust, 1978 (Box 17)
    - Foreign Travel. Mailing Addresses (Box 17)
    - Foreign Travel. Correspondence, 1977-1982 (Box 17)
    - Foreign Travel. Mexico, 1999-2003 (Box 17)
    - Foreign Travel. Spain, 1980 (Box 17)
    - Foreign Travel. Spain. "Correspondence and Papers", 1987-1988; undated (Box 17)
      Includes Leopold manuscript, "Leyendo el Paisaje".
    - Foreign Travel. Spain. Mailing Addresses (Box 17)
      Includes correspondence.
    - Genealogy Reference File (?) (Box 17)
    - Grand Canyon. American Wilderness Alliance, invitational Colorado River trip, 1981 (Box 18)
      Includes correspondence: Doherty, John (U.S. Representative, California), and Ranney, Sally A.
    - Guns (Box 18)
      Includes photos. Also includes correspondence: Clarke, Frank E., 1987 February 9; McCabe, Robert A., 1988 December 16; Weiss, Tim, 1987 April 28.
    - Hunting - Quail (Box 18)
      Includes correspondence of Justin Teeguarden, 1998 February 26.
    - "Ideas for Talks", undated (Box 18)
    - "Interview of Luna Leopold by John Hart, Berkeley, April 14, 2003", 2003 April 14 (Box 18)
    - Legal Suit re Landslide at Leopold Home, Berkeley, California, February 1998, 1998-1999; undated (Box 18)
      Includes legal correspondence and notes; Leopold notes on rainfall for February 1998; portion of geologic map, "Landslides of the Berkeley Hills"; diagrams and sketches of property.
    - Leopold, Aldo. Biographical Information (Box 18)
    - Leopold, Luna B. Vitae (Box 18)
    - "Leopold Delivers Inaugural Wolman Lecture" (Box 18)
    - Licenses. Aviation (Box 18)
    - Licenses. Fishing (Box 18)
    - Licenses. Hunting (Box 18)
    - Licenses. Registered Geologist (Box 18)
    - "Literary Allusions" (Box 18)
      Includes correspondence of Robert Bundgaard, 1994 September 3; John Graves, 1967 December 21; George H. Drury, 1960 December 12.
    - "Luna" (Box 18)
    - Music (Box 18)
    - Notes, Miscellaneous Papers (Box 18)
    - Mailing Addresses (Box 18)
    - "Papers to Read" (Box 18)
    - Politics, 1987 (Box 18)
    - Professional and Social Societies (Box 18)
    - Real Estate, 2004 (Box 18)
    - See-Through Crumbpickers Association, undated (Box 18)
      Includes copy of children's book, "Leopold: the See-Through Crumbpicker", by James Flora (New York, 1961), inscribed "To Our Chief", from "The See-Through Crumb-Pickers Association". Also includes poem by Leopold as "President, Treasurer, Chairman of the Membership Drive Committee, and Member, The Seethroughcrumbpickers Association".
    - Slack, Keith, 1990 (Box 18)
    - Spanish Language and Grammar Notebook, undated (Box 19)
      Affixed inside front cover is correspondence: Aráuz, Rodolfo, 1986 July 11.
    - Statement re Native Sonoma (Box 19)
    - Sylvan Bay Homeowners Association (Fremont Lake, Wyoming), 1969-1994 (Box 19)
    - Teaching. University of California at Berkeley, 1981 (Box 19)
    - Travel. Mailing Addresses of Others (Box 19)
    - Travel. Miscellaneous (Box 19)
    - Union of Concerned Scientists (Box 19)
    - University of California at Berkeley. Department of Geology and Geophysics. Review, 1980 (Box 19)
    - University of Colorado at Boulder Alumni Association. "Cruise the Face of Europe" Passenger List (Box 19)
      Annotated by Leopold.
    - Vita-Finzi, Claudio, 1996-2002; undated (Box 19)
      Includes Vita-Finzi manuscript, "The inconstant Sun".
- 2. Daily Calendars, 1958-2006 [intermittent]; 17.0 items (Box 20)
  Subseries 2 comprises pocket calendars and wall-hanging calendars with daily notations and records of activities, appointments, etc., for years 1958, 1975-1978, 1980, 1982, 1983, 1986, 1988, 1989, 1993, 1999, 2006. 17 items.
- VI. Leopold Family Papers, circa 1909-2006; 0.25 Linear feet 1 box
  Series VI comprises papers created by or otherwise related to the family of Luna Leopold; principally his father (Aldo) and his siblings.
  Of special note here is the notebook cover acquired by Aldo Leopold around 1909, which was used as a temporary housing for papers such as used in the field. It is the only Aldo Leopold artifact in the Luna B. Leopold Papers. Luna Leopold acquired it after his father's death and continued to use the notebook cover in the same fashion, meticulously listing trips on which he carried it in the U.S. and around the world, 1955-2004. Luna left this notebook cover filled with materials at the time of his death, which have been removed and foldered separately (see listing).
  - Bradley, Nina Leopold. Speeches. "Aldo Leopold and the Arboreteum", March 1982, 1982 March (Box 21)
  - Bradley, Nina Leopold. Speeches. Commencement, University of Wisconsin at Baraboo, 21 May 2005, 2005 May 21 (Box 21)
  - Bradley, Nina Leopold. Speeches. Environmental Law Conference, Eugene, Oregon, March 2002. "A Sense of Place", 2002 March (Box 21)
  - Bradley, Nina Leopold. Speeches. Wildlife Society Annual Conference, 26 September 2005, 2005 September 26 (Box 21)
  - Leopold, A. Carl. Academico de Honor (Real Academia Galega de Ciencias), 2000 (Box 21)
  - Leopold, Aldo. Notebook Cover., circa 1909-2006 (Box 21)
    Notebook cover originally used by Aldo Leopold, acquired by him circa 1909; subsequently used by Luna B. Leopold during worldwide travels, 1955-2004 (itemized by L.L. inside rear cover). Contents of notebook cover, as received from Luna Leopold, are removed and filed separately in subsequent folders.
  - Leopold, Aldo. Notebook Cover. Contents as last used by Luna Leopold. Folder 1, circa 2004-2006 (Box 21)
    Includes photos and correspondence. Includes Luna Leopold journal entry; poem by Luna Leopold.
  - Leopold, Aldo. Notebook Cover. Contents as last used by Luna Leopold. Folder 2 (Box-folder 21)
    Includes photos and correspondence.
  - Leopold, Bruce, 1950 (Box 21)
    Photocopy of cover sheet for 26th Annual Spring Banquet, Harvard University Geology Club, 27 April 1950. Photocoopy annotated, "Given to Bruce Leopold--March 2006--when we cleaned out the Berkeley House--M. Lpld [Madelyn Leopold] 3/15/06".
  - Leopold, Estella. Speech. "Ecologists and the Land Ethic. Presentation to the History Of Science Society, Nov. 3 1000 [2000] Vancouver BC (Oct 29 draft)", 2000 October 29 (Box 21)
  - Leopold, Nikia. Poetry, undated (Box 21)
  - Leopold, [undetermined]. Memorial of Aldo Leopold, 2005 January 8 (Box 21)
    By one of the children of Aldo Leopold.
- VII. Barbara Leopold (Mrs. Luna Leopold) Papers, 0.25 Linear feet 1 box
  Series VII comprises correspondence and papers gathered by Barbara Beck Leopold.
  - Aldo Leopold Shack Foundation, 1986 July 2 (Box 22)
  - Bagnold, Dorothy Plank (Mrs. Ralph A. Bagnold), undated (Box 22)
  - Balmuth, Millie (Mrs. William Balmuth), 1986 April (Box 22)
  - Bancroft School, 1985 July 23 (Box 22)
  - Bradley, Nina Leopold, 1984, 1989 (Box 22)
  - Breton, Hazel, 1994 March 11 (Box 22)
  - Campbell, Dorothy, undated (Box 22)
  - Ginger, Elaine M., 1977 May (Box 22)
  - Hemphill, Elyzabeth H., 1982 August 7 (Box 22)
    Includes photo (slide).
  - International Hospitality Center, 1978 November 7 (Box 22)
  - Leopold, Betty (Mrs. A. Starker Leopold), 1985 August 4 (Box 22)
  - Nelson, Carolyn T., undated (Box 22)
  - People for Open Space, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Rumsey, Bart, 1982 February 3 (Box 22)
  - Shumway, Charlotte, 2001 November 1 (Box 22)
  - Shute, Sharie, 2004 January 13 (Box 22)
  - Town and Gown Club, 1997, 1999, 2004 (Box 22)
  - undetermined, 1981-2000; undated (Box 22)
  - United States. Forest Service. Bridger-Teton National Forest. Dinner, 1982 (Box 22)
  - University of California. President, 1984 July 16 (Box 22)
  - University YWCA (Berkeley, California), 1985 December 20 (Box 22)
  - Vita-Finzi, Claudio, 2001 January 26 (Box 22)
  - Wyoming Federation of Garden Clubs, 1989 January 4 (Box 22)
- VIII. Research and Subject Files, 2.75 Linear feet 8 boxes, 1 vol.
  Series VIII comprises Luna Leopold's subject and specific research files.
  Subseries 1, General Research and Subject Files, is composed of files on various research focuses and research conducted in specific geographical areas.
  Subseries 2, Gaging Stations Data File, is a separate group of files kept by Leopold that contain data that relate to specific stream-gaging stations as established by the U.S. Geological Survey.
  Subseries 3 contains Leopold's separate data files that relate to his canyonbound-rivers research; specifically, Green River, Utah; Colorado River, Utah-Arizona; and Little Colorado River, Arizona (the files do not contain data for the San Juan River, Utah).
  Subseries 4, Rivers Data File (California) is a separate group of files kept by Leopold that contain data that relate to California rivers.
  Subseries 5, Rainfall Records contains precipitation data kept by Leopold wherever he resided, 1947-2006; although data are not recorded continuously.
  Subseries 6, Dissassociated Materials, is a group of reference and research materials found loose in the Luna Leopold Papers as received.
  - 1. General Research and Subject Files, 1.5 Linear feet
    - Acid Rain, Wyoming (Box 23)